Guide to the Spy Hop Productions independent film collection 2000-2009
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 25)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Exterior of Salt Lake City Tourist Bureau (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interior of Salt Lake City Tourist Bureau (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Display in the Salt Lake City Tourist Bureau of gold, silver, and bronze medals (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man wearing a San Francisco 49ers knit hat.
    Sign which reads "Polish Sausage" taped to a blue tarp (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Sign in front of Temple Square alerting visitors of the changes in Temple Square security during the Olympics (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Lamppost banners with the LDS temple on them and the LDS Church Office Building in the background (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Close up of lamppost banners with the LDS temple on them and the LDS Church Office Building in the background (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Spires of the Salt Lake LDS temple, zoom in on the Angel Moroni
    LDS Church Office Building art poster of a figure skater
    East facade of the Salt Lake LDS Temple
    Zoom out on glass sculptures "Sun" (yellow) and "Moon" (blue) by artist Dale Chihuly in front of Abravanel Hall
    Flags from countries around the world hanging from the balconies of an apartment complex downtown
    People visiting the "Wild West" exhibit on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building
    A man in the "Wild West" exhibit tells a folk tale about a young boy who steals a magic flute from a woodpecker
    Men in buckskin clothing sell handmade jewelry at the "Wild West" exhibit
    A young girl in a green native American-styled dress sits on a bench covered in animal skins at the "Wild West" exhibit
    A man in buckskin clothing selling handmade jewelry at the "Wild West" exhibit teases a young boy
    People in a crowd at the "Wild West" exhibit
    A blacksmith at the "Wild West" exhibit makes a horseshoe as he explains his craft to onlookers
    Children climb upon a stagecoach
    Olympic logo manhole cover
    People sit on ski lift-styled bench
    Jumbotron with a commercial for Merrill Lynch
    Welcome sign in various languages
    People stand in front of a stage on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building
    People sit on bleachers with the new county courthouse in the background
    Lights show partially visible through the trees
    People sit on bleachers, different perspective
    A young man with a Spy Hop baseball cap starts to speak
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 26)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Kids from Spy Hop play around with a camera and test sound equipment (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man as a website displayed in the background reads "The Olympic Rodeo" (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Tape corruption for several minutes
    Interview with a man, Pete Linster, on the street protesting the hypocrisy of the US's involvement in the Olympics while at war when other countries are boycotted for such actions during the games. Greenpeace flag sticking out of his backpack. (sound corrupted, sound returns approximately half way through the interview)
    Yellow sign "Thou shalt not terrorize"
    Interview with a man, Jeffrey Smith, on the street also protesting against the war in Afghanistan and Iraq
    A group of war protestors sing to an acoustic guitar while holding signs which read "What about the Olympic Truce? Stop the war," "Thou shalt not kill," "War =s terrorism," and "Thou shalt not terrorize" (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    One of the protestors steps forward to speak with the camera man briefly (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A police officer hands cards to each of the protestors to fill out (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Jeffrey Smith continues to speak with the cameraperson (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A young man in a cream suit performs R&B(?) on a stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young man, Robert Roveta, who works as a service employee for the Olympics. Roveta is asked his opinion about the Olympics as to whether or not he feels the games are worth the hype and how Salt Lake is being portrayed during the games. (sound corrupted, partial sound)
    Crowd watches lights from Caldron Stadium (Rice Eccles Stadium, University of Utah)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 27)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Framed Olympic logo
    Pan down over a building interior onto a framed Swedish flag
    Framed poster which reads "Sportsmanship, Self-Discipline, Friendship, Respect, Goals...SWEDEN, Our partner in one school one country"
    Interview with a woman volunteer who works as an Escort Supervisor for athletes to ensure that athletes aren't using performance enhancers including watching an athlete give a urine sample up to an hour after an event. (Sound corruption, sound levels very low)
    Interview with Marta Dunjova from one of the Slavic states who is living and working in Salt Lake City during the Olympics.
    Zoom in on Iceland flag on a building and a sign below which reads "Tomax Iceland House"
    Zoom in on the side of a building with multinational flags strung in a banner, as well as large posters of athletes on the wall
    A police officer greets crowds as they walk by
    "Green Jell-O" Olympic Pin on a board next to various other pins on a board being sold and traded by a vendor
    A man pulling a rickshaw down a street as people walk by on the sidewalk
    A band comprised of an electric bass, two violins, and an acoustic guitar, perform on a sidewalk outside the Utah Tourist Bureau
    A clown on a Main Street sidewalk makes balloon animals for a group of children
    People wait for Trax trolleys
    Pedestrians walk down a sidewalk on Main Street
    A Trax trolley arrives at a Main Street platform
    A flag hangs outside of the JVdge cafe
    Firemen pry up a vent in front of a business
    Firemen walk from a fire truck
    Zoom in on a fire truck light
    Pedestrians walk by as firemen survey a building
    Interview with a young man, Harold B. Branch III, a poet who works with youth in Chicago, teaching them life skills. Came to the Olympics when hired by Club Freedom to perform poetry but once here became much more involved in the games.
    People watch a jumbotron on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building the Closing Ceremonies performances (i.e. Kiss)
    Shot of Caldron Stadium (Rice Eccles Stadium, University of Utah)
    Shot of Caldron Stadium (Rice Eccles Stadium, University of Utah) as fireworks explode overhead during the Closing Ceremonies of the Olympics
    Shot of the Olympic Winter Games flag as fireworks explode in the background
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 28)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Chinese protestors in the Free Speech Zone hold yellow banners which read "Falun Dafa" with a swastika (sound corrupted, no sound)
    People practice Thai Chi in the Free Speech Zone at Pioneer Park (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a woman (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Chinese protestors in the Free Speech Zone hold banners which have various statements about "Falun Dafa" (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a man holding a sign which reads "Peaceful Appeal on TAM: 35 Western Practitioners from 12 Countries" (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Shot of woman previously interviewed, being interviewed again by a news crew from Channel 30 (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Close up of embroidered Asian characters which in English below reads "Falun Dafa" on a yellow background (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Chinese protestors in the Free Speech Zone hold banner which reads "Falun Gong Practitioners Welcome Olympics" (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Chinese protestors in the Free Speech Zone hold banner which reads "Protect the Olympic Spirit -- Stop the persecution of Falun Gong in China" (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview (#2) with a man holding a sign which reads "Peaceful Appeal on TAM: 35 Western Practitioners from 12 Countries" (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A sign which reads "Whosoever was not found written in the book of life was cast into the lake of fire..." (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Man wearing a yellow "Falun Dafa" scarf speaks to passersby on a mega phone (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A person on crutches limps away from the camera (sound corrupted, no sound)
    People hold signs with photos of people beaten by police officers for practicing Falun Dafa in China (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A man in a blue jacket yells out to the crowd and passes out small leaflets when he is approached by a volunteer with a volunteer "jersey" on, who tells him that he must stay in the designated area (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Man in blue jacket then speaks to a police officer who apparently tells him the same thing (sound corrupted, no sound)
    A man in a blue jacket begins to yell out to the crowd and pass out leaflets again, police officer speaks to man again momentarily (sound corrupted, no sound)
    People hold a blue "Falun Dafa" banner (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Close up of the swastika on "Falun Dafa" banners (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Crowd of "Falun Dafa" supporters hold pictures of practitioners brutalized by police in China (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young Chinese woman wearing a yellow "Falun Dafa" scarf (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Chinese protestors walk out of the Free Speech Zone at Pioneer Park hold banners which have various statements about "Falun Dafa" on a march through Salt Lake (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a young Chinese woman wearing a yellow "Falun Dafa" scarf previously interviewed, being interviewed again by a news crew from Channel 30 (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Close up, bicycle racks (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Chinese protestors walk holding a banner which reads "America, thank you for your support" (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Banner on a building which reads "Greek Orthodox Community Welcomes the World" (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a woman, Iuni Wolfgramm, involved in Polynesian dancing at the Olympics. Wolfgramm is asked what Polynesian dancing has to do with the Olympics and her role in that.
    A young girl, Kansas Begae, plays a Native American flute while a young boy plays a drum on stage
    Kansas Begae then plays drum and sings on stage
    Kansas Begae plays a Native American flute while a young boy plays a drum on stage
    Kansas Begae sings as young boy plays drum on stage
    Interview with Native American singer/musician, Kansas Begae about her involvement in the Olympics and her performance.
    Interview with an older man in a gray fleece jacket (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 29)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Night footage from a moving vehicle of the University of Utah Campus, the Eccles Olympic Memorial Bridge, in particular
    Freedom of speech meeting at the Gould Auditorium in the Marriott Library (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Freedom of speech fliers on a table (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Freedom of speech meeting at the Gould Auditorium in the Marriott Library (sound corrupted, no to partial sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 30)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Children sing on the steps in front of the Virgin mega store at the Gateway in downtown Salt Lake City
    A man talks on a cell phone at the Olympic Water Sculpture at the Gateway
    Statue of a skier entitled "Go For the Gold" located by the Olympic Water Sculpture at the Gateway
    Shot of a professional film crew on break
    Interview with a young man named Marcus from Salt Lake City. Marcus gives his opinions about the Olympics in Salt Lake and how Salt Lake Olympic Committee (SLOC) is trying to sell a particular image of Salt Lake.
    Rock water fountain at the top of stairs by the Virgin Mega Store at the Gateway Mall
    Shot of the Gateway sign on the Rio Grande Building
    Interview with a young man, Mike Watson from Las Vegas who lives in Salt Lake, wearing a black and red knit cap. Mike sees the Olympics as a positive opportunity for the city however believes that the locals don't support it as much as they should.
    Interview with Jody Chambers from Ottawa, Canada. Champers sees Salt Lake as very friendly and the Olympics as an opportunity to build bridges of international friendship.
    Exterior shot of Roots Olympic clothing store.
    Artist decorated buffalo statue wrapped in "filmstrip" on the second level of the Gateway Mall
    A horse drawn carriage passes a school bus in downtown Salt Lake City
    Kodak film promotion on a bus followed by another bus decorated with the US flag
    Shot of people looking at the "Host City" map of events and venues
    Kodak film promotion on a bus
    Light post banners with the Olympic logo on them
    Vender booth advertising Olympic pins, souvenirs, and collectables
    Olympic ring logo banners on poles
    Exterior of the Delta Center, people milling around outside, pan right (north) down 300 West
    An ice sculptor speaks to someone off camera; zoom in on a sculpture of what appears to be an alligator
    Samsung video display
    Shots of athlete billboards around the area of the Delta Center
    Shot of the Chevy trailer which accompanies the torch bearers
    Exterior Delta Center
    Large image of women speed skaters on the side of the Olympic Super Store building
    Shot of the Kodak trailer
    Olympic banner
    Official Olympic Marching Band, pan then pan and tilt up to a banner of an athlete
    Coca-Cola building, exterior
    People outside Delta Center
    People walking down street (South Temple near 200 West?)
    Shots of Gateway exterior, Rio Grande Building
    Coca-Cola statue of a downhill skier
    Zoom east down South Temple and end on a building banner of an athlete
    Shots of Gateway exterior
    Tilt up of sponsor board listing companies (i.e. Kodak, Coca-Cola, and John Hancock)
    Delta Center exterior
    People walking around West Temple
    Shot of a cargo van with a large picture of a 10 week gestation aborted fetus
    Interview with the man driving the anti-abortion van. Man asked why he has come to the Olympics.
    Exterior shot of Ethnic Village, pan left to a handwritten sign which reads "Everyone welcome"
    Two men playing guitar and singing in Spanish as a young woman stands between them
    Sign which reads "Hispanic Americans: Entertainment stage, demonstrations, exhibit"
    Gift shop displaying Native American items
    Interview with a man carving a Polynesian totem (sound corrupted, low sound level)
    Interview with a man in a blue jacket, Earl Franklin, working as a bus driver for the Olympics
    Interview with Harold Brice III, a poet from Chicago who works with young people (see also item 27).
    Young girl shakes hands with a "mountain man" while her parents take a picture on the grounds of the Salt Lake City and County Building
    Interview with "mountain man" named Crazy Coyote who explains the "mountain man" and Native American exhibit for those visiting Salt Lake to educate visitors on what life was like for Native Americans and fur trappers and traders who lived in the area before the pioneers came.
    Interview with a man named George "Two Hawk" Knowlend, a Salt Lake resident, about the Olympics coming to town and about the culture and Olympic inflation of goods and services (i.e. Olympic merchandise, hotel rooms, food, etc.)
    George "Two Hawk" Knowlend shows some of the Native American clothing he has on display at the Wild West exhibit
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 31)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Large group of people sitting around in what appears to be an expo area (perhaps the field house) at the University of Utah campus as they await their performance in the opening ceremony
    Exterior shot, two men in army fatigue stand by a chain link fence
    Sign which reads, "All Wardrobe Volunteers please go to the Tennis Center! Thanks! Room 106"
    Various shots of people in the crowd
    Native American dancer does a hoop dance in the crowd as others watch
    Various shots around Caldron Park before either the opening ceremony
    Various shots of the Olympic Caldron at Caldron Park
    Various shots around Caldron Park before the opening ceremony
    Extreme close up of US Flag next to Olympic Flag
    Interview with a young woman working in operations for the Ceremonies Committee
    Interview with a young man in a red shirt
    Various shots of people dressing in their costumes for the opening ceremony
    Various shots of people walking down North Temple
    A man holds a yellow sign which reads "The Olympics, public expense, corporate profit"
    Man holding sign explains it to a woman walking by
    A road worker in a yellow Olympic parka talks to people holding a "Citizen Activist Network" banner
    Interview with a man named Dayne Goodman who is with the Citizen Activist Network explaining why he and others from his group are at the Olympics
    Man in a red and black coat speaks to a young woman in a yellow coat, Amy Hines (sound corrupted, low sound levels)
    Interview with Amy Hines who is also with the Citizen Activist Network and gives further information concerning what the Citizen Activist Network hopes to achieve by coming to the Olympics
    Interview with Scott Cowley from the Citizen Activist Network
    Shot of police officers in yellow Olympic parkas riding on horse
    A man in a blue and black jacket holds a sign which reads "Corporate Domination (left pointing arrow), Democracy (right pointing arrow)"
    Shot of a US flag with all of the stars replace by corporate logos
    Man pulling a rickshaw
    Press conference with Mayor Rocky Anderson (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Interview with a Canadian man whose wife is a referee in the women's hockey competition
    Shot of a building with Swiss flags and a mural of the Alps, Swiss cattle and men playing Alpine Horns, mural says "Come in and Celebrate with us!"
    Exterior, front of a building (Swiss House) with Swiss flags on top, a US flag over the door and flag-like banners strung across the front
    Press conference at the Swiss House spoken in German
    Exteriors, rooftops and flags, various shots
    Coca-Cola parade float (icebergs with coke bottles)
    "Host City: Salt Lake 2002" sidewalk pyramids
    Shot of the Coca-Cola Polar Bear vehicle with a person dressed as the Polar Bear waving to the crowd
    Budweiser billboard
    Event Parking $10.00 sign on a sidewalk
    Budweiser neon sign in the window of a bar, wooden shutters behind sign
    Shot of Trax trolley
    Coca-cola painted sign on the side of building on the corner of 400 South and Main Street
    Corner shot of 400 South and Main Street, people wait while two Trax trolleys pass
    People pass by map information sign on 400 South
    Grounds worker for the Olympics sweeps around trees
    AT&T Wireless American Red Cross First Aid Station
    Main Street (?) facing south, shot from sidewalk as crowds pass information pyramid in background.
    Main Street (?) facing south, shot from sidewalk as crowds pass refreshment pyramid in background.
    Trax trolley on Main Street as another type of trolley passes it
    "Great fondue. Coming soon. The Melting Pot." sign on the building where the Melting Pot was under construction.
    Temporary bus stop sign
    US and Swiss flags flying on and around the Swiss House, Olympic House
    Atlantic Mediterranean Cuisine resturaunt front with various flags flying over the awning
    People walking down Main Street.
    Pan up of a tall building downtown
    Close up of a US flag
    Shot of Main Street as people walk by
    Sign on the front of a building which reads "Casa Italia - Torino 2006"
    Utah and Us flags flying above a building on Main Street which has a shop on the ground floor selling Olympic merchandise
    Budweiser banners outside of the Budweiser World Party venue
    People exiting Trax
    Drama masks on an Olympic pyramid
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 32)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with Craig Bradley, an Olympic volunteer involved in opening and closing ceremonies by calling about rehearsals and working as a VIP for the talent by picking up musicians such as Sting, Yo-yo Ma, and the Dixie Chicks.
    Shot of the Salt Lake City airport baggage claim area
    Salt Lake City airport airline desks and desk lines
    Exterior Salt Lake City airport, night, pick up area
    Shot of the Olympic ring logo on a glass partition, outside of Terminal 1 at the Salt Lake City airport
    Terminal 2 baggage claim area, Salt Lake City airport
    Shots from the moving walkway leading from baggage claim area to the parking garage
    Indoor parking pay booth, Salt Lake City airport
    Parking garage Terminal 2, Salt Lake City airport
    Teens driving out of the Terminal 2 parking garage at the Salt Lake City airport and toward downtown Salt Lake City
    Shot from a moving vehicle of a countdown jumbotron sponsored by Coca-Cola
    Shots of downtown streets from a moving vehicle, night
    People waiting along a street as a drum band passes, night
    Shot of lights scaffolding
    Hip hop song and dance group performs on stage
    Tahitian hula dancer performs on stage
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 33)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Children's dance group performs on the medals plaza stage
    Women doing a Polynesian dance
    Men doing Polynesian "slap dance"
    Shots of Polynesian items for sale such as tropical flowers, shell jewelry, etc.
    New Zealand dancers perform
    Tahitian dancers perform
    A young Tahitian girl performs a dance as members of the audience come on stage and stuff dollar bills on her clothing
    Four young women perform a vocal number on stage
    Exterior, night, a person sits alone on bleachers as the camera pans out on a small crowd listening to a band perform on the medals plaza stage (sound corrupted, no sound)
    Refreshment vendor tent
    Country band performs on a small "Old West-like" stage
    A blacksmith stokes his fire while working on a piece as he talks to a crowd
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 34)
  - Raw footage for the Spy Hop documentary, "Messages: 2002 Olympic Diary" (Video 1)
    Interview with a man in a striped green dress shirt (sound corrupted, no sound)
- Salt Lake City Winter Olympics documentary raw footage, 2002; Mini-DV videocassette (Cassette 35)